<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>About environment-dependent problems</title>

<para>
<ptitle>Environment-dependent bugs</ptitle>
This is the problem of Kirikiri and its countermeasures caused by the environmental problem of the end user (secondary user).<r/>
We make every effort to avoid environment-dependent problems in the production of Kirikiri, but since the computer settings and configurations are so diverse, environment-dependent problems will inevitably occur.<r/>
In some cases, it is possible to deal with individual symptoms, but in general, please take the following measures.<r/>
<ul>
<li>Make the driver the latest stable one</li>
<li>Remove resident items (especially those that easily conflict with other software, such as antivirus software, memory cleaner software, window appearance changing software, Windows compatible shell, etc.)</li>
<li>Check your computer with various check tools ("Check disk" (OS standard disk check tool), <at  target="_top" href="http://www.memtest86.com/">memtest86</at>, etc.)</li>
<li>Check if there is enough free space on the HDD</li>
<li>Refer to <at target="_top" href="http://homepage2.nifty.com/winfaq/">WinFAQ</at> (Oda's page) and look for similar symptoms, and take action accordingly</li>
<li>Once in safe mode, restart in normal mode</li>
<li>If you are using a CPU accelerator, certain features of the CPU may be limited, so please read the CPU accelerator manual carefully, and in some cases you may need to disable individual CPU functions in the engine settings (Example: For <at target="_top" href="http://buffalo.melcoinc.co.jp/qa/cpu/b4590010.html">http://buffalo.melcoinc.co.jp/qa/cpu/b4590010.html</at>, disable SSE)</li>
<li>Reinstall the OS</li>
</ul>
Most of the options that can be set for the Kirikiri engine are for dealing with environment-dependent bugs. See also <link href="CommandLine"/>.<r/>
</para>


<para>
<ptitle>Environment-dependent symptoms</ptitle>
In the following, "engine setting" refers to an end-user setting tool (engine setting.exe).<r/>



<dl>




<dt>The installed data is corrupted</dt>
<dd>Symptoms include reading error errors such as "Reading error", "Freezing while running the work", "EAccessViolation error", and other unpredictable behavior.<r/>
There is a possibility that the installed data is corrupted. Please use "File Corruption Check Tool" etc. to check if the installed data is damaged.</dd>


<dt>Freeze when switching or skipping screens</dt>
<dd>
If the screen freezes when screen drawing occurs frequently, such as when switching screens (at transition) or skipping with KAG, there may be a problem with the display driver.<r/>
Please make sure that the display driver version is the latest stable version, and if it is older, please change to the latest stable version.<r/>
Alternatively, it may be improved by changing the setting of "Double buffering method" or "Vertical synchronization wait" in "Engine settings".<r/>
If you are using "nView Desktop Manager", a utility that comes with your nVIDIA graphic card, please uninstall or disable this utility.<r/>
</dd>

<dt>Screen drawing is abnormally slow</dt>
<dd>
In particular, when the image is enlarged and displayed by Kirikiri when full screen, or when double buffering is explicitly enabled, if the screen drawing is abnormally slow, use the "double buffering method" in "Engine Settings". Changing the setting of "Waiting for vertical synchronization" may improve the situation.<r/>
Also, if the enlargement is performed on the engine side instead of on the monitor side, performance may degrade with the enlargement. In this case, if you set "Screen resolution at full screen" to "Nearest resolution" in the engine settings, enlargement will be performed on the display side, but depending on the display, images may not be displayed with the correct aspect ratio there is.
</dd>

<dt>The screen remains black or the image is distorted</dt>
<dd>
Especially when Kirikiri enlarges the image at full screen, the screen remains pitch black, or if the image is disturbed or freezes, "Double buffering method" in "Engine Settings" It may be improved by changing the setting of "vertical syncronization wait".<r/>
</dd>


<dt>Video playback fails</dt>
<dd>
If the overlay fails to play the video (displays an error or freezes) or freezes immediately after playing the video, disabling hardware acceleration may help. Displayed by pressing the "Advanced" button in the "Settings" tab of "Display Properties" (a dialog box displayed by selecting "Properties" from the context menu displayed by right-clicking on the desktop) Please move the knob of "Hardware Acceleration" on the "Troubleshooting" tab of the dialog box from the maximum to the direction of "None" and try again.<r/>
It is also recommended that you set the script to not play the video.<r/>
Alternatively, it may be improved by changing the setting of "Double buffering method" or "Vertical synchronization wait" in "Engine settings".<r/>
</dd>

<!--
 ###This disappeared because the driver information was not seen just by loading DirectDraw###
<dt>Kirikiri core tries to connect to the network when trying to make it full screen</dt>
<dd>If you try to make it full screen, security software may warn you when Kirikiri core tries to connect to the Internet.<r/>
Kirikiri loads DirectDraw for the first time when going to full screen, but then checks the DirectDraw driver version. At this time, we may connect to crl.microsoft.com to confirm the validity of the driver signature. This is done when "Check for revocation of issuer certificate" in the "Advanced" tab of Internet Options ([Tools]-[Internet Options] from Internet Explorer) is checked.<r/>
This symptom occurs when the OS refers to information on the Internet to verify the validity of the driver's digital signature. It is the OS that actually makes the connection, but as that function of the OS operates within Kirikiri's program, it may appear that Kirikiri is trying to connect to the Internet as a result. Please be assured that these are not spyware-like processes.<r/>
If the end user is worried, either uncheck the "Check for revocation of the issuer certificate" mentioned above, or prohibit connection to the address using security software. There is no effect on the operation of Kirikiri itself.<r/>
</dd>
-->

<!--
 ###I think that this problem has disappeared because the full screen related algorithm of Kirikiri has been improved.###

<dt>Screen stretches vertically or horizontally when full screen</dt>
<dd>When the screen is full screen, the screen stretches vertically or horizontally, and the screen is not displayed with the normal aspect ratio (aspect ratio). In particular, the environment that uses the liquid crystal display. For example, if you try to make a 640x480 or 800x600 screen full screen with a wide LCD panel or SXVGA LCD panel, this may happen.<r/>
In this case, refer to the hardware manual and make settings so that the image can be enlarged (full screen display) while maintaining the aspect ratio.<r/>
Some liquid crystal displays have a function to enlarge the display while maintaining the aspect ratio on the liquid crystal display side, so please set according to the manual.<r/>
Also, depending on the graphic card (graphic chip), the driver can enlarge the image while keeping the aspect ratio, so please set according to the manual.<r/>
Even with the functions of the Kirikiri core, full screen can be achieved while maintaining the aspect ratio. If you set "Graphic-Screen resolution at full screen" to "Do not change screen resolution" in the engine settings, you can switch to full screen while maintaining the aspect ratio.<r/>
</dd>
-->



<dt>Intermittent or no sound, or freezes during sound playback</dt>
<dd>Depending on the sound card and the environment, the sound may be choppy and interrupted, noise may be heard, or sound may not be heard midway. In some cases, the sound may freeze only while the sound is playing.<r/>
If it occurs during a transition (switching screens) or heavy effects, set "General-Low Priority" to "Yes" in the engine settings, or set "General-CPU Reduction" to "Yes". It may be improved by setting to.<r/>
In addition, it may improve even if you change the setting of "Sound-DirectSound software mixing" in the engine settings.<r/>
Alternatively, open "Advanced" of "Sound Playback" on the "Audio" tab of "Multimedia" (or "Sounds and Multimedia" or "Sound and Audio Device Properties") in the control panel, and open the "Performance" tab. Please try moving the "Hardware Accelerator" slider gradually toward "None".<r/>
</dd>

<dt>Operation is not successful</dt>
<dd>If software such as mouse movement support or mouse gesture realization tools is resident, you may not be able to operate the work. Please cancel the resident of such software.<r/>
If a third-party (non-OS standard) mouse driver is installed, it may cause problems in the operation system. In such a case, disable or uninstall the third-party driver and use the OS standard driver.<r/>
If a gamepad (joystick) is connected to the gamepad compatible software, you may not be able to operate the work due to a malfunction of the pad. Make sure that the button on the pad has not been pressed because something is on the pad.<r/>
Also, if the game pad (joystick) is not connected, there is an environment where the pad button is detected as being pressed. In such a case, please disable the pad driver.<r/>
Incorrect operation of the center of the gamepad or joystick axis may cause malfunctions. In this case, please adjust the game controller from "Game controller" on the control panel.<r/>
If you can not disable the pad driver by all means, you can disable the pad on the Kirikiri side. Please set the "pad availability" to "do not use" in the engine settings.<r/>
If you are using a third-party mouse driver, you may not be able to type on the wheel. In this case, setting "Mouse wheel rotation detection method" to "Window message" in the engine settings may improve the situation.<r/>
</dd>


<dt>Frequent thrashing</dt>
<dd>Thrashing (a lot of swap-in / swap-out) can occur frequently due to lack of memory.<r/>
It may be improved by setting "General-Memory usage" to "Low" in the engine settings.<r/>
However, performance will be reduced, so do not change the option for "General System-Memory Usage" and set "Graphics-Image Cache Limit" to a relatively low value such as "4 MB" or "8 MB" so memory usage may be reduced without significantly degrading performance.<r/>
</dd>







</dl>

</para>


</doc>
