<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>Kirikiri setting</title>

<para>
<ptitle>About Kirikiri setting</ptitle>
　"Kirikiri Settings" is a tool that allows you to set Kirikiri options with a GUI.<r/>
　This is so that end users (secondary users) can do some troubleshooting and performance tuning themselves.<r/>
　The engine settings are started by adding -userconf to the Kirikiri executable file itself.<r/>
<r/>
　The name of the option, the value that can be set, and the description of the option use the information built into the Kirikiri core.<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>About configuration files</ptitle>
　There are two types of configuration files for Kirikiri. The file that is located in the same location as the Kirikiri executable file, with the extension of the executable file name changed to <kw>cf</kw>, and the name of the executable file that is placed in the data storage location specified by -datapath of <link href="CommandLine"/> It is two of those that changed the extension to <kw>cfu</kw>.<r/>
　The cfu is generated by "engine settings (-userconf)" for end users.<r/>
　When setting with Releaser, a .cf file will be created. However, please note that if you do not distribute this file together with Kirikiri, the set options will not be reflected.<r/>
　If these files do not exist, they will be created when you launch the engine settings and press the OK button.<r/>
<note>
In the configuration file, 'name="value"' is described line by line. The "value" part is a series of \xNN, each of which is a code point value in UNICODE. For example, if you write opt = "\x61\x62\x63\x3042\x3044\x3046", this means "abcあいう". Be careful when writing to these files from other applications.<r/>
In addition, if you write without using the \xNN format like opt="abcあいう", the Kirikiri core can recognize this correctly, but the engine setting cannot recognize this format. It may not work as expected. Double quotes on both sides of the value are also required.
</note>
</para>


<para>
<ptitle>Engine settings screen</ptitle>
　The engine setting screen will be as follows.<r/>
<r/>
<img src="Configure.png"/><r/>
<r/>
<dl>
<dt>"Option Name"</dt>
<dd>
　The available options are listed.<r/>
　See also <link href="CommandLine"/>.
</dd>

<dt>"Optional Values"</dt>
<dd>
　A list of option values that can be set for the option selected in "Option name" is displayed.<r/>
　Please select.
</dd>

<dt>"Description of Options"</dt>
<dd>
　Displays a description for the option selected in "Option Name".
</dd>

</dl>
</para>


</doc>
