<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>Copyright etc.</title>

<para>
<ptitle>Copyright / License</ptitle>
　See license.txt included with the SDK.<r/>
　Here are some copyright and licensing FAQs or things that many will ask.<r/>
　The principle is as described in license.txt, so be sure to read license.txt.<r/>
　If there is a conflict between what is written here and what is written in license.txt, what is written in license.txt takes precedence.<r/>
<r/>
<dl>
<dt>Do I have to pay the creator of Kirikiri?</dt>
<dd>
　You don't have to.
</dd>

<dt>I want to use it for commercial use (including shareware) ...</dt>
<dd>
　Also available for commercial use.<r/>
　No license fee is required for commercial use. Available free of charge.
</dd>

<dt>I would like to borrow a name from the work...</dt>
<dd>
　In particular, there is no need to write in the documentation that you used Kirikiri.<r/>
　Of course, you can write it (^^;<r/>
　Unless otherwise stated, the license indication displayed in -about cannot be deleted.<r/>
　When the license indication is described in the document etc. according to the modified BSD license, the license indication displayed by -about can be deleted.
</dd>

<dt>When the work is completed, do I need to inform the author of Kirikiri?</dt>
<dd>
　There is no obligation to notify that you used Kirikiri. There is no obligation to notify you, even for commercial use.<r/>
　But I'm glad to say a word, yes.
</dd>

<dt>I would like to modify the Kirikiri source...</dt>
<dd>
　Kirikiri Z is a modified BSD license. Sources can also be modified under the modified BSD license.
</dd>
</dl>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Acknowledgments</ptitle>
　Kirikiri 2 and Kirikiri Z are established with the cooperation of many people. Thank you for your kindness.<r/>
　In particular, Mr. PIA received a lot of advice regarding Kirikiri / KAG. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
　Kirikiri Z was developed by crowdfunding and with the financial support of many people.<r/>
　The people who helped me (in no particular order) are W.Dee, casper, MCF, Biscrat, Blue Cat, nagai, Lou, Masayuki Takagiwa, Eternity, Yun Yun Detective, Ryogo , AZ-UME, Akito Kyo, Katsumasa Tsuneyoshi, Jun Koike, miahmie, Circle Baku, Azanashi, Hashi, Tananaka, Waffle / waffle, Wamsoft, TYPE-MOON, M2.<r/>
<r/>
　Go Watanabe provided various plugins including the Win32Ole plugin. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
　Kenjo provided Photoshop-compatible blend functions. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
　The gamepad code was provided by Kiyobee. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
　Kouhei Yanagita provided the KAGParser class documentation and KAG extensions. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
　The Kirikiri icon is by MIK. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
　Various functions related to movie playback, such as layer-based movie playback, incorporate "movie expansion" by Takemoto Imoto. Thank you very much.<r/>
<at target="_top" href="http://www.kaede-software.com/">http://www.kaede-software.com/</at><r/>
<r/>
　The blur implementation is based on the code provided by yun. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
　Mr. mey provided pad-related enhancement patches, String.reverse(), etc. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
　The following is a list of programming libraries / support software used by Kirikiri (in no particular order, without titles). Thanks to those who have published useful libraries.<r/>
<r/>
<dl>
<dt>IJG JPEG Library (Independent JPEG Group)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.ijg.org/">http://www.ijg.org/</at><r/>
    This software is based in part on the work of the Independent JPEG Group.
</dd>

<dt>libpng (Guy Eric Schalnat, Andreas Dilger, Glenn Randers-Pehrson,  and others)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.libpng.org/pub/png/libpng.html">http://www.libpng.org/pub/png/libpng.html</at>
</dd>

<dt>zlib (Jean-loup Gailly, Mark Adler)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.gzip.org/zlib/">http://www.gzip.org/zlib/</at>
</dd>

<dt>ERINA-Library (L.Entis)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.entis.jp/eri/">http://www.entis.jp/eri/</at><r/>
    ERINA-Library Copyright (C) 2001 Leshade Entis, Entis-soft.
</dd>

<dt>Regex++ (Dr John Maddock)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://ourworld.compuserve.com/homepages/John_Maddock/regexpp.htm">http://ourworld.compuserve.com/homepages/John_Maddock/regexpp.htm</at><r/>
    Regex++ Copyright (c) 1998-2000 Dr John Maddock
</dd>

<dt>UPX (Markus F.X.J. Oberhumer &amp; Laszlo Molnar)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://upx.sourceforge.net/">http://upx.sourceforge.net/</at>
</dd>

<dt>Shell Component Library (Takashi Ito)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.bekkoame.ne.jp/~itotaka/">http://www.bekkoame.ne.jp/~itotaka/</at>
</dd>

<dt>NASM, The Netwide Assembler (Simon Tatham, Julian Hall and others)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://nasm.sourceforge.net/">http://nasm.sourceforge.net/</at>
</dd>

<dt>alink (Anthony A.J. Williams)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://alink.home.dhs.org/">http://alink.home.dhs.org/</at>
</dd>

<dt>md5.c (L. Peter Deutsch)</dt>
<dd>
    Copyright (C) 1999, 2000, 2002 Aladdin Enterprises.  All rights reserved.
</dd>

<dt>libogg/libvorbis (Xiph.Org Foundation)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.xiph.org/">http://www.xiph.org/</at><r/>
    <r/>
Copyright (c) 2002, Xiph.org Foundation<r/>
<r/>
Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
are met:<r/>
<r/>
- Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.<r/>
<r/>
- Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the
documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.<r/>
<r/>
- Neither the name of the Xiph.org Foundation nor the names of its
contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from
this software without specific prior written permission.<r/>
<r/>
THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS
``AS IS'' AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT
LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR
A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE REGENTS OR
CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL,
EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,
PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR
PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING
NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS
SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
</dd>


<dt>Ogg Vorbis Acceleration project</dt>
<dd>
Kirikiri 2 uses the SSE-compatible FFT calculation code published in Ogg Vorbis Acceleration Project by blacksword inside Phase Vocoder.
<at target="_top" href="http://homepage3.nifty.com/blacksword/">http://homepage3.nifty.com/blacksword/</at><r/>
</dd>

<dt>A C-program for MT19937 (Makoto Matsumoto and Takuji Nishimura)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.math.keio.ac.jp/matumoto/emt.html">http://www.math.keio.ac.jp/matumoto/emt.html</at><r/>
    <r/>
Copyright (C) 1997 - 2002, Makoto Matsumoto and Takuji Nishimura,
   All rights reserved.     <r/>

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
are met:<r/>
<ol>
<li> Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.</li>

<li> Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the
documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.</li>

<li> The names of its contributors may not be used to endorse or promote 
products derived from this software without specific prior written 
permission.</li>
</ol>

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS
"AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT
LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR
A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT OWNER OR
CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL,
EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,
PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR
PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING
NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS
SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.<r/>

</dd>


<dt>LibTomCrypt (Tom St Denis)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://libtomcrypt.org/">http://libtomcrypt.org/</at><r/>
</dd>





<dt>AGG (Anti-Grain Geometry)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://antigrain.com/">http://antigrain.com/</at><r/>
<r/>
The Anti-Grain Geometry Project<r/>
A high quality rendering engine for C++<r/>
http://antigrain.com<r/>
<r/>
Anti-Grain Geometry - Version 2.3 <r/>
Copyright (C) 2002-2005 Maxim Shemanarev (McSeem) <r/>
<r/>
Permission to copy, use, modify, sell and distribute this software 
is granted provided this copyright notice appears in all copies. 
This software is provided "as is" without express or implied
warranty, and with no claim as to its suitability for any purpose.
</dd>



<dt>Expat</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://expat.sourceforge.net/">http://expat.sourceforge.net/</at><r/>
<r/>
Copyright (c) 1998, 1999, 2000 Thai Open Source Software Center Ltd
                               and Clark Cooper<r/>
Copyright (c) 2001, 2002, 2003, 2004, 2005, 2006 Expat maintainers.<r/>
<r/>
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining
a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the
"Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction, including
without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish,
distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to
permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to
the following conditions:<r/>
<r/>
The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included
in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.<r/>
<r/>
THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF
MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.
IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT,
TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE
SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
</dd>



<dt>Oniguruma</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.geocities.jp/kosako3/oniguruma/index_ja.html">http://www.geocities.jp/kosako3/oniguruma/index_ja.html</at><r/>
<r/>
Copyright (c) 2002-2007  K.Kosako ( sndgk393 AT ybb DOT ne DOT jp )
All rights reserved.<r/>
<r/>
Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
are met:<r/>
<ol>
<li> Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.</li>

<li> Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the
    documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.</li>
</ol>
THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE AUTHOR AND CONTRIBUTORS ``AS IS'' AND
ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE
IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE
ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHOR OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE
FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS
OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION)
HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT
LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY
OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF
SUCH DAMAGE.
</dd>




<dt>FreeType</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.freetype.org/">http://www.freetype.org/</at><r/>
Copyright 1996-2002, 2006 by David Turner, Robert Wilhelm, and Werner Lemberg
</dd>



<dt>picojson</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="https://github.com/kazuho/picojson">https://github.com/kazuho/picojson</at><r/>
<r/>
Copyright 2009 Cybozu Labs, Inc.<r/>
<r/>
Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:<r/>
<ol>
<li> Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice,
    this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.</li>

<li> Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice,
    this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation
    and/or other materials provided with the distribution.</li>
</ol>
THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY CYBOZU LABS, INC. ``AS IS'' AND ANY EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF
MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO
EVENT SHALL CYBOZU LABS, INC. OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT,
INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES
(INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES;
LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND
ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT
(INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF
THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.<r/>
<r/>
The views and conclusions contained in the software and documentation are
those of the authors and should not be interpreted as representing official
policies, either expressed or implied, of Cybozu Labs, Inc.
</dd>


</dl>
</para>

</doc>


